翻譯: Jamie Amber sumsmit
你說科特·柯本把吉他扔下來 砸到你頭了嗎
So Kurt Cobain threw his guitar and he hit you in a head?
涅槃樂隊主唱、吉他手
- 沒錯 - 太棒了
- Yep. - Amazing.
校對: 不賣萌斯基
天啊 在我失去知覺前那十秒
Oh my god. The ten seconds,
簡直真的是"涅槃"了
before I passed out, was actual "Nirvana."
我看過個"吸血鬼周末"的演唱會偷錄版
I went once to a bootleg of a Vampire Weekend concert,
美國搖滾樂隊
后期: UU123
那股原始能量仿佛要從耳機里掙脫出來
and that raw energy just shot out of those earbuds.
壓制: B B
"耳機" 天啊 我真該掌你嘴
"Earbuds"? Oh, my god. I should slap you in the mouth.
Eve 你必須得去
No, eve, you have got to be
現場才能真正領會到演唱會的魅力
there to get the full experience of a live concert.
我媽就這樣 只要她認為是她自己的想法
One thing about Mom... she'll let you do anything
她什么都會允許你做
if she thinks it's her idea.
好吧 既然你都提了 吸血鬼周末
Well, now that you mention it, Vampire Weekend
- 要來紐約了  - 噢 哇哇哇
- is coming to town... - Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
不行 我都說過不許去了
No, I already said no to this.
她把你當猴耍呢
She's working you like a speed bag.
- Eve  - 媽 幫幫我嘛
- Eve. - Mom, help me out here.
我想要回憶 想要感受沖擊(腦震蕩)
I want memories. I want a concussion.
這兩者還能兼得嗎
Isn't that an either/or thing?
不 聽著 我跟你爸是同一戰線的
No, listen. Your Dad and I are a team.
他說不行 就是不行
If he says no, the answer is no.
走吧 親愛的 離預約的時間只有十分鐘了
Let's boogie, honey. Reservation's in ten minutes.
- 不好意思啦 寶貝  - Mike Annie 我有句話跟你們說
- Sorry, kiddo. Sorry. - Mike, Annie, a word.
我也有一句 不行
Here's one... - No.
漂亮 這就是Henry家族難以抑制的智慧
Great stuff, Dad. There's that irrepressible Henry wit.
就花你們一點時間 我想要重新修改
This will only take a nano. I wanted to revisit the whole
"Graham睡大房而我睡小房"這個方案
Graham-gets-the-big-room- I-get-the-small-room issue.
我準備了個小小的PPT演講
I made a tiny powerpoint presentation...
你智商有150
You have an I.Q. Of 150.
為什么要花時間和精力
Why are you wasting your
在這糾結誰睡大房呢
time and energy on who gets a bigger room?
我在創業啊 而且我智商是152
I'm trying to start a business... 152, P.S.
還有 老待在這么小的房間 睡在賽車床上
And by the way, how am I supposed to feel like an adult
很難感覺到我已經是個大人了啊
when I'm in this tiny room sleeping on a race car bed
可Graham卻在大房間 玩假裝地面是火山熔漿的游戲
and Graham's in that huge room pretending the floor is lava?
Lucy 不 來人啊 救命啊
Lucy! No! Guys, help!
- 噢 寶貝  - Lucy已經死了
- Oh, sweetie. - Lucy's gone.
- 我們先逃命吧  - 噢
- Let's save ourselves. - Oh...
我已經開始想念孩子們了
I miss them already.
才怪
I totally don't.
- 不好意思  - 沒事
- Excuse me... - It's okay.
噢不 我不是對你說"不好意思"
Uh, no, that wasn't "Excuse me."
我是覺得你應該說"不好意思"
I was going for, uh... "Excuse me?"
- 哦 好吧  - 你看起來不很樂意啊
- Okay, I got it. - Doesn't seem like you do.
我來跟你講解電梯是如何運作的吧
Let me explain to you how elevators work.
叮 電梯門開了
Ding. Elevator doors open.
里面的先出來 然后新乘客才進去
The people inside exit, and then the new passengers come in.
幾千年來都是如此
It's been that way for thousands of years.
- 也沒有幾千年啦  - 說完了吧
- Well, thousands... - Are we done?
本來完了 但你又補了這句
Uh, we were... until you said that.
- 這家伙能更扯點嗎 Mike  - 呃
- Can you believe this guy, Mike? - Uh...
Annie有股強烈的正義感
Annie has a strong sense of justice.
而我只強烈希望能與鄰居融洽相處
I have a strong sense of wanting to get along with my neighbors.
可在這種場合 我能說Annie什么嗎
But can I say something to Annie in these situations?
- 不能  - 聽著 我不知道你
- No, I cannot. - Listen, I don't know what cave
以前活在哪個原始山洞里的...
you dragged your knuckles out of...
- 親愛的 我們的預約  - 但在這幢樓里
- Honey, our reservation... - ...but in this building...
人人都要有禮貌 聽懂沒
we believe in manners, okay?
很明顯你是初來到文明社會
You're apparently new to manners and society...
- 有興趣一起出去吃晚飯嗎  - 呃
- Do you wanna go out to dinner? - Uh...
好啊
Yeah.
又 見 彩 虹
第一季  第六集
電波誠譯
剛見到上次在電梯遇到的人 超冷淡
Just saw the elevator guy... total cold shoulder.
我問他到幾樓 他自己按了樓層
I asked him what floor. He pushed his own button.
真抱歉 親愛的 我知道你多
I'm sorry, sweetie, I know how you like
喜歡按電梯按扭
to push those buttons yourself.
只要我夠得著
Well, the ones I can reach.
該死 Harris發來的 說有個卡拉OK派對
Crap. It's Harris. It's about the karaoke party.
我突然很懷念退休的日子
Suddenly I miss being retired.
每年 Mike的老板就喜歡
Every year, Mike's boss bundles
把員工的生日弄到一個大型卡拉OK派對上一起慶祝
all the staff birthdays into one big karaoke party.
其實就是為了滿足
But it's really just his
自己打扮和在人們面前唱歌的私欲
excuse to get up and sing in front of a crowd.
他總是打扮成自己喜愛的歌手
He's been known to dress like his favorite musical acts.
而我們總是搬出各種缺席的借口
And we've been known to come up with excuses for why we can't go.
有了 就說我大姨媽去世了
I know. I'll say my great aunt died.
這個06年已經用過了
Yeah, we used that one in '06. Hey...
- 就說我發燒了  - 這個不錯
- I could come down with a fever. - That's great.
這么一來 我還不用回答其他附帶問題
That way, I don't have to answer any follow-up questions,
例如"你大姨媽叫什么"
like "What was your aunt's name?"
關于看演唱會的事 你們太不講理了
You guys are being totally unreasonable about the concert.
- Amy的家人還說會載她去呢  - 哪個家人
- Amy's family offered to drive. - Family?
她那個22歲胡子都長到脖子上的哥哥嗎
Try her 22-year-old brother with a full neck-beard.
- 猜猜我干了什么  - 你買了條狗啊
- Look what I just got. - You got a dog?
我是在說我新弄的頭發 不過的確 我買了條狗
Oh, I was referring to my blowout, but, yes, I did get a dog.
這小東西可以幫我增加點男人緣哦
This little guy is gonna help me meet guys.
- 那你可以叫它破冰者  - 這個好
- You should name him Icebreaker. - Genius!
給小孩取名不太是你的強項
Naming children really isn't really your thing,
- 不過這個不錯  - 還記得Banjo嗎
- but you nailed it. - Remember Banjo?
還記得小時候你帶回家的Banjo嗎
Remember you brought home Banjo when we were kids?
結果是誰在照顧Banjo呢 是我
Who ended up taking care of Banjo? I did.
我怎么有預感事件會重演呢
Why do I have a feeling that's gonna happen again this time?
現在Leigh姑姑已經是個有判斷力有責任心的成人了
Aunt Leigh is a responsible adult with good judgment.
完全有能力照顧一只寵物
She's perfectly capable of owning a pet.
你不覺得她對這狗就三分鐘熱度嗎
You don't think she's gonna flake on this dog?
說了這么久我有多不靠譜 還是沒說說我的發型
A lot of talk about how I'm a flake, not a word about my blowout.
不是覺得 我知道
I don't think it. I know it.
要不 我們賭一次
In fact, I'm willing to bet on it.
如果我贏了 我可以去看演唱會
What do you say... if I win, I get to go to the concert.
- 我喜歡這種穩贏的賭局  - 等著瞧
- I love a bet I can't lose. - You're on.
就像跟小朋友打賭一樣沒挑戰
This is going to be like going to a concert from a baby.
噢 該死 你怎么在這里
Oh, come on! What are you doing here?
你得去啊 Mike 我是說
You got to be there, Mike. I mean, it's not just
那不僅僅是個省錢的群體生日會
a money-saving mass birthday party. It's a celebration
還是個古日本卡拉OK的文化盛宴
of the ancient Japanese art of kara-o-kay.
- 絕不容錯過哦  - 聽起來不錯哦
- You can't miss that. - Well, as awesome as that is,
問題是 Annie可能把感冒傳染給我了
uh, I-I-I... the thing is I think Annie's gotten me sick too.
該死 Mike 我們還喝了同一杯奶昔
Oh, damn it, Mike. We split a milkshake.
你這是在害我啊 我明天還要演唱呢
Man, what are you doing to me? I got to sing tomorrow.
不是叫你用另一根吸管嘛
I told you to get an extra straw.
Harris 聽著 我得走了
Harris, listen, I got to run.
身體允許的話 我會盡量去的
We'll be there... health permitting.
這天氣可真夠受的是吧
This is some weather we're having, isn't it?
是啊
Yeah.
我這么說
When I say that, I'm not
不只是隨便閑聊而已 我是做新聞的
just making small talk. I work in the news.
有氣象臺的內部消息
I've got access to a Doppler 9000, so...
Doppler 9000 氣象雷達
關于昨晚 我的妻子Annie 她有點
Uh, about last night, my wife, Annie, she got a little...
- 暴躁  - 有點
- snippy. - A little?
她教訓了我一整路啊
She lectured me the entire elevator ride,
還跟到我家門口
followed me to my door...
其實是我鄰居家門
Well, my neighbor's door, actually.
- 我才不想讓她知道我住哪  - 明智
- I didn't want her to know where I live. - That's good thinking.
事情是這樣的 Annie最近不太好
The thing is, Annie's going through a rough patch.
- 什么意思  - 就是 她有點...你懂的
- What do you mean? - Well, she's a little... you know.
- 我不懂  - 她最近停藥了
- No, I don't. - She's a little bit... off her meds.
我完全沒想到 她還好吧
Oh. I had no idea. Is she okay?
她實際上 不太好 不好
Well, she's... not really, no.
情緒非常不穩定
No, it's terrible mood swings.
一天好 一天壞的
One day, yay! Another day, boo.
- 抱歉 她是躁郁癥嗎  - 對 就是這個
- If I may ask, is she bipolar? - Yes. Perfect. Exactly.
她是典型的躁郁癥 就是這個
She's... she's classic bipolar. It's a whole thing.
真抱歉 我是精神科醫生 天天和這種病打交道
I'm so sorry. I'm a psychiatrist. I deal with that all the time.
那我們就不用多說了
Oh, so we don't have to talk about this anymore.
我能問一問她在接受什么藥物治療嗎
If I may ask, um... what kind of medication is she on?
就是那些圓圓小小藥片 有的和你頭一樣大
Oh, uh, round ones, small ones, ones as big as your head.
別說我的惡夢了
But enough about my nightmare.
你那什么信啊
What kind of mail do you got there?
嘿 兄弟 大房間很好吧
Hey, buddy. Enjoying the big room? Oh...
爸爸的原話是"Graham想對他的房間怎么著
Dad's exact words were "Graham can do whatever
就怎么著" 大概是這樣啦
he wants with the room"... or something like that.
因此 如果我能說服他把房間給我
Ergo, if I get Graham to want to give me the room,
那就歸我了
hmm, it's all mine.
這個房間發生過很多事啊 好的
So much happened in this room... good things...
- 可怕的  - 可怕的
- some scary things. - Scary things?
噢 沒什么好說的
Oh, hardly even worth talking about.
就是貓幽靈什么的
Like Shadowpuss.
- "貓幽靈"  - 嗯 這是我的叫法
- "Shadowpuss"? - Well, that's what I called him.
他的真實名字是人類無法發出的音
His real name can't be made by human vocal cords...
就是很典型長著貓臉的地獄生物
basically your average cat-faced hell creature
- 同時有著惡魔的身體  - 噢
- with the body of a demon. - Hmm.
就等上鉤了
The hook was set.
沒錯 過去夜里經常出現一只老貓 就在那個門后面
Yep, used to see the old puss at night, right behind that door.
傳說他會吃掉你的內臟
Legend has it he would eat your entrails and keep you
讓你眼睜睜看著他擺弄糟蹋你的玩具
alive to watch while he played carelessly with your toys.
我的床周圍有火山熔巖保護
Well, my bed's surrounded by a lava force field.
貓幽靈就是在火山巖里出生的
Well, Shadowpuss was born in lava,
所以那阻止不了他 好自為之吧 再見
so that's not really gonna be a problem for him. Bye!
好了 今天就這樣吧 一共是175美元
Oh, well, that's our time for today. That'll be $175.
喂 那是我的臺詞
Hey, that's my line.
嘿 Annie
Hey, Annie.
昨天還沒有自我介紹呢
I don't think we were properly introduced
我是Bill
the other night... I'm Bill.
哦 很高興見到你 Bill
Well, it's very nice to meet you, Bill.
還有 我是個精神科醫生
By the way, I'm a psychiatrist.
如果你對你的藥有任何疑問 我就在樓上 15B
If you have any questions about your meds, upstairs in 15-B.
- 我的藥  - 好了 Bill
- My meds? - Come on, Bill.
已經沒有在計時了 公歸公私歸私
You're off the clock. Leave work at work.
Mike跟我說的我會嚴格保密的
What Mike told me was in strictest confidence.
- 只想告訴你 你可以來找我  - 呃 很好
- I just want you to know I'm a resource. - Well, good.
好的
Okay.
躁郁癥 得多上點心啊
Bipolar disorder... is a serious matter.
躁郁癥
Bipolar disorder?
還是得聽聽別人的意見嘛
We can get a second opinion.
我不敢相信 你居然告訴那家伙我有躁郁癥
I can't believe you told that guy I was bipolar!
我們怎么知道你沒有呢
Well, do we know for a fact you're not?
聽著 我只是不想鄰居討厭我們
Look, I'd just prefer if our neighbors didn't hate us.
我只是想幫你收拾
I mean, I was just trying to clean up your...
"殘局" 我的殘局
"Mess"? My mess.
- 你就想這么說吧  - 我打算漸弱處理的
- You were about to say "My mess." - I was gonna just trail off.
有時候你待人太不友善了
Sometimes you're a little hard on people,
我不得不一次次去補救
and I have to smooth things over from time to time.
一次次 所以你以前也做過了
Time to time? So you've done this before?
呃 在大樓里那次
Well, in the building and...
地鐵上那次 還有兒童動物園那次
on the subway and, uh, at the petting zoo.
不管你是不是五歲
I don't care if you're five.
不能騎駱駝就是不能騎
You're not supposed to ride the llama.
我會教訓舉止粗魯的人
Yes! I call people out on their rudeness!
我不認為這有什么問題
I don't think there's anything wrong with that!
人們可以把我看成文明社會
You know, one could argue that I am all that stands
和混亂之間的堅實守護者
between civilized society and chaos.
- 你是蝙蝠俠嗎  - 我是你妻子
- You're Batman?! - I'm your wife.
我們該統一戰線啊
And we're supposed to be a team.
那并不意味著我要盲目贊同你
That doesn't mean I'm gonna blindly agree
即便我知道你是錯的
with everything you say even if I think you're wrong.
- 真的嗎 所以你...  - 不要這樣拉長句子
- Really? Is that why... - Don't stretch out words like that,
- 讓我覺得很不安  - 不不不 沒事
- because it's... that's unsettling. - No, no, no. It's good.
我只是很高興知道
It's just good for me to know
我們不再互相支持了
that we no longer have to get each other's backs.
很好 很好 很好 很好
Good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good.
好 好 好 好極了
Good, good, good, good!
這樣更不安了
That's even more unsettling.
這是我住的地方 那是煮飯的地方
This is where I live. This is where I cook.
- 酷  - 那是工作的地方
- Cool. - This is where I work.
嗯 很好
Hmm. Good stuff.
這里 是你吻我的地方
And this... is where you kiss me.
- 你好 Leigh姑姑  - 啊
- Hello, Aunt Leigh. - Aah!
Eve 你不能就這樣溜進別人的公寓
Eve! You can't just sneak into somebody's apartment like that.
- 相信我 我差點被槍殺了  - 嗨 你好嗎
- Trust me. I've been shot at. - Hey, how's it going?
嘿 小家伙在這呢
Hey! Here's the little guy!
Bandit不在這兒真可惜
Oh! I bet you wish Bandit was here.
- 對嗎 對的  - 你剛才去哪了
- Don't you? Yes, you do. - Where were you?
狗跑出去了 我在樓下大廳找到的
The dog got out. I found him in the lobby.
樓管不肯幫我修門
The super won't fix my door.
我覺得他一直溜進來偷我的內衣
I think he's sneaking in and stealing my underwear.
我最近干的活一點錢都沒賺著
I am working without a net right now.
- 這家伙是誰  - Gary
- Who is this guy? - Gary?
昨天在狗狗公園遇到的
I met at the dog park yesterday.
破冰者起作用了 成功破冰
Icebreaker already worked... ice broken.
嘿 能幫我照看一下小狗嗎
Hey,do you mind watching Icebreaker?
我和Gary需要一點成人時間
Gary and I were gonna have a little adult time,
可是 破冰者保護欲太強了
but, you know, Icebreaker is very protective.
它可能會以為媽媽受傷了
He might think Mommy's getting hurt.
我覺得這借口沒"最近干活沒賺著錢"好
I didn't think you could top "Working without a net."
- 要不我去問下你爸  - 別 好吧 我來照看它
- I guess I could just ask your Dad. - No! No. Uh... I'll do it.
演唱會最好給我精彩點
This better be a good concert.
你最棒了 幫我個忙
You're the best. Listen, do me a favor.
走的時候 跟這家伙自我介紹一下
On your way out, introduce yourself to this guy,
因為我只有九成把握他叫Gary
because I'm only 90% sure his name's Gary, okay?
我已經在Graham腦中埋下了貓幽靈的種子
I had planted the seed of Shadowpuss in Graham's mind.
現在我要做的就是收獲恐懼的果實
Now all I needed was to harvest my crop of terror.
系緊安全帶咯
Strap in.
聲音文檔明顯載錯了
That's obviously the wrong sound file.
這是什么鬼東西啊
What the hell is this?
嘿 怎么啦 發生什么事啦 孩子們
Hey, hey, what's going on? What's going on, guys?
- 我做了這個來嚇貓幽靈  - 什么貓幽靈
- I made him to scare Shadowpuss. - What's a Shadowpuss?
是住在我房間里一只恐怖的貓惡魔 Ian 快告訴他
He's a scary demon cat that lives in my room. Ian, tell him.
你是認真打算嚇你弟
Are you seriously trying to scare your brother
- 讓他跟你換房間嗎  - 我要睡大房 爸
- into switching rooms with you? - I need a bigger room, Dad.
你都不把我當回事
And you're not taking me seriously.
- 你手上拿著個貓木偶呢 - 這不是個木偶
- You're holding a cat puppet. - This is not a puppet.
它可以展現38種不同的情緒
It's capable of 38 distinct emotions.
我現在真是有38種情緒了 Ian 自豪可不在里面
I feel 38 emotions right now, Ian, and not one of them is pride.
拉下它的尾巴 看有什么發生
Pull its tail. See what happens.
不 我才不要拉
No, I'm not gonna pull its tail!
聽著 你想我們把你當成人對待
Look, you want to be treated like an adult,
那就別再糾結誰睡大房 計劃下將來
stop worrying about who gets a bigger room and find a path.
- 我有計劃的  - 是嗎 你從大學輟學
- Oh, I have a path. - Really? You dropped out of college.
你在這四個月了 還沒收你房租
You've been here four months, rent-free. I mean, you're
Ian 你很聰明 可是專注力放錯了地方
a smart kid, Ian, but you're focusing on the wrong things.
- 還給我  - 不行
- Give me this. - No...
Graham要有充足睡眠 他是我最后的希望了
Graham's got to get some sleep... he's my last hope.
- 啊  - 發生了什么
- Aah! - What was that?
- 他拉了那尾巴  - 真是
- He pulled its tail. - Son of a...
躁郁癥
Leigh姑姑的狗在這干嘛
What's Aunt Leigh's dog doing here?
我把它帶來給你看看
I... brought him here to show you what a good
Leigh姑姑把它照顧得多好
job Aunt Leigh's been doing of taking care of him.
她現在和Gary在大西洋城
She's in Atlantic City with Gary...
那人其實叫Steve
whose name turned out to be Steve.
演唱會就在今晚 我想我贏了
And since the concert is tonight, I guess I won the bet.
- Leigh姑姑呢  - 找獸醫去了
- Where is Aunt Leigh? - She's... at the vet.
- 不帶狗去嗎  - 你
- Without the dog? - You...
你可不能把狗帶到獸醫診所啊
You can't take a dog to a veterinary clinic.
要知道 空氣里到處是犬類病毒
You know, all those... those airborne canine viruses.
況且 城里正開貓咪大會呢
Plus, there's that cat convention in town...
了解 演唱會沒戲
Got it. No concert.
我認為 Eve應該去看演唱會
Actually... I think Eve should go to the concert.
- 什么  - 我一直都是同意的
- What? - I never had a problem with it.
Eve那么聰明 我相信她的判斷力
Eve's smart. I trust her judgment.
她不用非得贏了賭局才能去
She shouldn't have to win a bet to go.
- 等一下  - 太好了
- Hang on. - Awesome.
在你們改變決定前我先走了
I'm getting out of here before that answer can change.
- 我不懂 我們決定好的啊  - 不不 那是你的決定
- I don't understand. We decided. - No, no, no, no. You decided.
我以為我們是同一戰線的才支持你的
I backed you up because we're a team.
可現在 我們之間不需再"盲目附和"
But now, since we don't have to always
我也可以有自己意見
"Blindly agree," I can give my own opinion.
我要給Harris打個電話
You know, I think I'm gonna give Harris a call.
- 不不 別打  - 就打
- No. No, you wouldn't. - Yeah.
不 聽著 把Eve推向了龍潭虎穴是一回事
No, look, it's one thing to throw Eve into harm's way,
可卡拉OK 我倆就得一起進龍潭虎穴啦
but karaoke... you'd be going down with me.
就像瓊斯鎮一樣
It'll be like Jonestown.
人民圣殿教教徒集體自殺慘劇之地
至少這是他們都同意的啊
At least they were a team.
嗨 Harris 我是Annie
Harris, hi. It's Annie.
嘿 你知道嗎 我的感冒突然痊愈了
Hey, you know what? My fever just broke.
好的 今晚見
Well, then we will see you tonight!
好吧 這是狗吃過的
Okay, that's been in a dog's mouth.
- *我們兩心相依*  - *眼里只有你*
- *That is what we are* - *No one in between*
- *眼里只有你*  - *未來會怎樣*
- *no one in between * - *how can we be wrong?*
*伴我去遠航* *駛向太平洋*
*sail away with me* *to another world*
- 下一個就是你咯  - 是啊
- You realize you're up next. - Oh, good.
得趕緊早藥效過去前把歌唱完
I can get my song in before my meds wear off
然后像Claire Danes一樣在這兒撒瘋
and I get all Claire Danes in here.
<國土安全>女主扮演者 片中患有躁郁癥
你知道那只是她演的角色而已
You know, that's just a character she plays.
我看過她上艾倫秀 真人挺好的
I saw her on Ellen. She was... she was lovely.
美國一檔脫口秀節目
你真的要上去嗎
You're really gonna go through with this?
- 我是說 你已經證實了你的觀點  - 謝謝大家
- Well, you've proved your point. - Thank you, thank you.
- 咱倆都知道你不喜歡卡拉OK  - 好啦
- We both know you hate karaoke. - All right.
感謝Kay Costa扮演的多莉·帕頓
Let's hear it for Kay Costa as Dolly Parton!
好了 下一位
All right, next up...
熱烈歡迎首次在這舞臺演唱的 Annie Henry
Ah, for the first time on this stage, we have Annie Henry!
再也沒有機會退縮咯
Last chance to back out.
知道嗎 Mike 我就是要上去
Well, you know, Mike, I think I'm gonna just go up there
秀出我最好的表演
and give it my best shot.
NBC4臺 今夜一起跟著音樂搖滾起來吧
NBC4, we are gonna rock this place tonight!
躁郁癥嗎
Bipolar disorder?
連這也拿出來開玩笑 Claire Danes才是
That's nothing to joke about, man. Claire Danes has that.
不 她沒有 她只是個才華橫溢的演員而已
No, she doesn't. She's just an incredibly gifted actress.
我猜猜 肯德基爺爺嗎
Let me guess... Colonel Sanders?
肯你個頭 Doug 說說看肯德基爺爺唱了什么歌
Pull your head out, Doug. Name one song by Colonel Sanders.
- 美味吮指歌嗎  - 那又不是他的歌
- The finger-lickin' good song? - That's not a song.
美味吮指歌 由Beastie Boys主唱
我扮的是肯尼·羅杰斯 哪涼快去哪吧 Doug
I'm Kenny Rogers. Keep moving, Doug.
美國鄉村音樂歌手
為什么你不跟Annie道歉
I just don't get why you don't apologize to Annie.
為啥 我還能怎么做
For what? What was I supposed to do?
那是我們的鄰居啊
The guy lives in our building.
所以比起你老婆 你更關心你的好鄰居咯
So you're more concerned about your neighbor than your wife?
還有 那個傳說中不喜歡卡拉OK的人
And by the way, for somebody who supposedly hates karaoke,
看起來很享受嘛
she sure seems to be enjoying herself.
看著她在臺上
Seeing her up there,
我才發現她并不是要跟我對著干
I realized she wasn't trying to make a point.
她真的喜歡卡拉OK
She actually loved karaoke.
而這些年來她一直假裝不喜歡
She'd just been pretending to hate it all these years
僅僅是為了和我統一戰線
to be a team player.
好嘞
All right.
- 再次感謝Annie Henry  - 謝謝大家
- That was Annie Henry... - Thank you!
和她這首超長版<Hit Me With Your Best Shot>
With a very extended version of Hit Me With Your Best Shot!
下一位是
And next up...
哦 瞧瞧
Oh, look at that.
又是Annie Henry
It's Annie Henry...
- 又是她 - 還來啊
- Again. - Two in a row?
"一整晚"這句唱的可真恰當
"All Night Long" Is right.
- 什么時候能輪到我唱啊 - 我要站在Annie那邊
- When will I get to sing? - I wanted to have Annie's back
就跟這么些年來她一直站在我這邊一樣
the way she's had mine all these years.
輪到我了
It's my turn now.
然后出現了一個絕好的機會
And then an opportunity presented itself.
- 你干嘛呢 Doug - 我只是
- What the hell, Doug? - I-I just...
Annie是報過名的 你怎么能在她唱歌的時候搶話筒呢
Annie signed up. You can't cut her off in the middle of a song.
這可不是你的專場秀 Doug
It's not all about Doug, Doug.
頭一回 我知道Annie為什么喜歡朝人大喊了
For the first time, I got why Annie loves calling people out.
確實是一種沖動
It's... it's kind of a rush...
但是我也有可能會有些過激
although it's possible I might have gone a bit too far.
而且還有 Doug 如果你不這么粗魯
And another thing, Doug... if you weren't so rude,
你可能就不會是世界上最老的實習生了
you might not be the world's oldest intern.
- 哦 不 - 還有你猜怎么著
- Oh, no. - And guess what.
- 沒人想要看你的即興演出 - 該死 Mike
- Nobody wants to see your improv show. - Aw, damn it, Mike.
現在我不得不看"注意:前方高能"了
Now I got to go see Caution: May Contain Nuts.
油管上一檔神經病脫口秀節目
Mike Doug準備幫我
Um... Mike? Doug was gonna do
- 伴唱Jambo Jambo那部分呢 - 我在單子上的
- the "Jambo Jambo" Part for me. - I'm... I'm on the sheet.
哦 是么 這是你名字 Doug D-o-u-g
Oh, yeah, there you are. Doug, D-o-u-g.
好吧 Jambo Jambo
All right, Jambo Jambo.
- 算了 我不想跳了 - 報名了就要來 Doug Jambo
- No, I'd really rather not. - Respect the sheet, Doug. Jambo!
來嘛 Jambo
Come on, Jambo.
Eve 快點 我們走
Eve, come on. Let's go!
快點 我們就要晚了
Come on, we're gonna be late.
該死
Damn it.
這就是為啥我總避免喜歡上什么
This is why I try not to like things.
嗨 哈嘍
Hi. Hello.
多謝你毀氣氛啊 Mike
Thanks for killing the vibe, Mike.
- 變裝整個啥用都沒有了 - 抱歉了
- A whole costume change for nothing. - I'm sorry.
我只是想要支持你 你知道的 和你一樣
I-I just wanted to have your back, you know, do what you do.
我可不是這么干的 我是對著他們的壞習慣大喊
That's not what I do. I call people out on their bad behavior.
你竟然對一個無辜的45實習生開槍
You took a shot at an innocent 45-year-old intern.
- 他才32 - 哇哦
- He's 32. - Wow!
得多喝點水啊
Have a glass of water every now and then.
好吧 我可能
Okay, I may have gone a
對電梯那個男的有點過分了
little too far with the guy in the elevator.
- 是的 罵了十層樓吧 - 盡管如此 經歷了今晚
- Yeah, about ten floors. - Even so... I think after tonight
很明顯還是我比較善于與人對質
it's obvious that I am better at confrontation.
- 好吧 我倒是一點都不享受 - 真的 我挺喜歡的
- Yeah, I didn't enjoy that at all. - Exactly. And I love it.
我有個瘋狂的想法
So here's a crazy idea...
要不從今往后 咱就固守自己擅長的活兒
how about from now on, we just stick to what we do best?
我來對付混蛋
I'll take on the jerks,
你來保證我們還會被邀請進派對
and you make sure we still get invited to parties.
成交 不過這個派對大概泡湯了
Done. Although I think this one's off the table.
會計部的Alice一直想用眼神殺死我
Alice from accounting keeps giving me the death stare.
哦 那個不用管 我來搞定她
Oh, don't worry about it. I'll take care of her.
Eve 你怎么沒去音樂會啊
Eve. Why aren't you at the concert?
為了贏得賭注 我一直偷偷在養破冰者
I've been secretly taking care of Icebreaker to win the bet.
Leigh姑姑的事 老爸說的對 我正要出門的時候
Dad was right about Aunt Leigh. I was on my way out,
看見狗狗在大廳里 于是就這樣了
and I saw the dog in the lobby, so here I am.
- 把狗繩子給我 - 什么
- Give me the leash. - What?
你媽媽是對的 你有自己的判斷
Mom was right. You do have good judgment.
- 去吧 去音樂會吧 - 真的嗎 謝謝你 老爸
- Now, go to the concert. - Seriously? Thanks, Dad!
哦 這會是我的"涅槃"時刻
Oh, this is going to be my Nirvana moment.
只要不是"紅辣椒"時刻就成
As long as it's not your Red Hot Chili Peppers moment.
也是美國搖滾樂隊
- 我搶到了他們四個人的襪子 - 那快走吧 都9點了
- I got all four socks. - So hop on a train. It's 9:00.
你應該還能趕上最后一首歌
You should be there for the last song.
他們的音樂會一般都會超過11點的
Oh, they don't even go on until 11:00.
- 他們怎么著 - 趁著你們沒改主意
- They don't what? - I'm getting out of here
我先撤了
before that answer can change.
嗨 你買了治療狗啊
Hey! You got a therapy dog.
真不錯 Annie
Good call, Annie.
滾蛋吧 Bill
Suck it, Bill!
不罵白不罵
I'm just gonna own it.
- 嗨 老爸 - 嗨
- Hey, Dad. - Hey.
你說得對 我一直把精力放在錯誤的事兒上
You were right... I've been focusing on the wrong things.
但是這個月初 你會收到我的租金支票
But first of the month, you're gonna get a rent check.
我還有一點康奈爾大學退還我的飯錢
I got a little money back when Cornell refunded my meal plan.
好吧 那其實還是我的錢
Yeah, that's actually my money.
對 但是我還把貓幽靈放網上賣了500刀
Right, but I also sold Shadowpuss on Craigslist for $500.
你跟買家說尾巴的事兒了嗎
Did you tell them about the tail?
我覺得買家不會需要這功能的
I don't think they're going to be using it for that.
- 買家只問我能不能洗 - 老天
- They asked if it's washable. - God.
還有我準備找份工作
And I'm going to get a job too.
實現我的夢想也許還有一段路要走
It might take a little longer to reach my dream,
但是 我已經是成人了 你覺得租金多少比較合適
but, hey, I'm a grown-up. What do you think is fair rent?
紐約平均水平來說
In New York City? Ballpark?
- 1200刀 - 不是 我說的可是小房間
- $1,200. - No, I'm talking about the tiny room.
我也是
So am I.
一家人其實就像跟一個團隊一樣
Being in a family is kind of like being on a team.
- 嗨 小家伙 - 怎么了 你眼睛都紅了
- Hey, little guy. - What's going on? Your eyes are all red.
我剛剛跟Gary分手
I just broke up with Gary.
我看到他親他家狗的樣子 太深情了
I saw the way he kissed his dog... very thorough.
從來沒那么親過我
He'll never kiss me that way.
你不一定能挑你隊友
You don't always get to pick your teammates...
我都哭了一整天了 關鍵是我根本不喜歡這男的
I've been crying all day, and I didn't really even like this guy.
我覺得你是對狗狗過敏吧
I think you're allergic to the dog.
拜托 Michael 我對自己的狗狗
Oh, please, Michael. Don't you think
過不過敏 我還不知道么
I'd know if I was allergic to my own...
不 你說的對
No, you're right.
我不能把破冰者送回去了
Oh, but I can't take Icebreaker back to the pound.
而且你也不會贏得每一場比賽
...and you might not win every game...
你想讓我養狗嗎
You want me to take the dog?
不 我才不是那種人
No, I don't want to be that person that...
但是不論發生什么 你們都要一起渡過
But no matter what happens, you go through it together.
養一個吉祥物也沒什么
And it doesn't hurt to have a mascot.
嗨 各位 我們家要有狗狗了
Hey, everybody, we got a dog.
- 讓我看看 - 哦
- Let me see! - Oh.
我猜這狗不用付租金吧
I bet the dog doesn't have to pay rent.
當然了 它跟你住
That's 'cause he's sharing your room.
電波字幕組 歡迎您的加入
官方網站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@電波字幕組